Ken Eucker

keneucker@gmail.com
https://linkedin.com/in/keneucker
https://github.com/keneucker
https://keneucker.com

About Me

I am a full stack developer, classically trained in object-oriented programming, who likes to write universal javascript, with experience building everything from the backend of web-connected properties to the frontend of the user experience. I have a diverse set of skills writing in the serverside languages C#, PHP, Javascript, and the clientside languages TypeScript, Javascript, HTML/CSS, JSX, including the datastore languages Redis, MySQL, MSSQL, and MongoDB.

The latter half of my career has been split between working with Nodejs and building WordPress applications, both headless with React and on Wordpress VIP working with popular plugins and themes. I have developed and launched WordPress 5.0 applications on self-hosted small business websites as well as enterprise applications on WordPress VIP.

I also spend a lot of my time dedicated to Free and Open-Source projects on GitHub. I am a collaborator as well as a maintainer of several different npm packages. I manage a grassroots organization entirely open-sourced via GitHub projects and I connect teams of people all over the world. I am a developer's developer and I love building tools for development, so I do everything DevOps and more on my personal projects, including automated test suites, gitflow with conventional commits, and automated releases using GitHub actions.

What I am looking for in my career right now

I am looking to both mentor and be mentored, to grow into leadership roles that suit me, and to discover yet to bloom talents and interests I may have above a programming level. I still want to continue to, and will never really stop, writing code and I am comfortable in both the backend as well as the frontend. I am accomplished in my experience with WordPress, as the first portion of my career, but have a decade of experience in NodeJs and if I am writing code these days I prefer to be writing universal JavaScript.

I want to write more Open-Source code for companies, especially those that are already using other Open-Source projects. Give me an engineering project and I'll give you a SAAS platform, allow me to Open-Source it and we can share it with the world.

Ultimately, it's not about the money or the benefits or the coolness factor. What my career means to me is this: the ability to grow and explore tech with others, to make a positive impact in the lives of the people my work touches, and to be able to engineer solutions to all the problems; both new and old. I want the autonomy to drive product development as well as being able to architect systems at scale, but I expect to be on a team of other people in tandem with the ebb and flow of life. We're all in this together.

Experience

N

N Senior Software Engineer

Nerdery

Jun 2021 - Jan 2023 (1 year 7 months)

I'm a Nerd who coaches team members and friends, engineers solutions for both backend and frontend teams, and oversees development processes for the NodeJs domain at The Nerdery. I came to Nerdery with a decade of experience in NodeJs and a willingness to get involved in everything I can from the updating of coding style standards to the defining of NodeJs roles across all of Nerdery. I cover all sorts of tasks from admin to documentation, DevOps and developer workflow process building, honing requirements and creating tasks for other team members, programming features and bug fixes in both BE and FE environments, meeting with project managers and client managers for everything from SOWs to resource management, and lots more.

I'm a Nerd through and I really do enjoy working with all of the wonderful people I have met at Nerdery. It's been 100% remote since the start, and I expect it will remain that way indefinitely, but I do look forward to a time in the future where I can meet my wonderfully friendly Nerds somewhere in the real.

My primary initiative at Nerdery is to build up and grow the culture of Open-Source as well as the amount of involvement in Open-Source that Nerdery can participate in. I want to see us be able to share and be proud of the tools we use as well as make meaningful contributions back to those communities that we are also a part of. I want to see us on the map of organizations that are known for their support for and participation in the Open-Source community.



Co-Founder

BikeTagOrg

Apr 2018 - Present (3 years 10 months +)

Co-Founder of the BikeTagOrg organization and Lead Architect for the website and web application.

I developed the BikeTag Platform entirely from scratch in Node.JS as the sole software engineer and developer on the project. What is now a set of 4+ open source repositories on GitHub, is a platform for running BikeTag games which supports BikeTag games all over the world on a single server -- yet is built in such a way that each individual game can be isolated onto its own infrastructure. Using as many free and open-source enabled technologies, I was able to build and scale this web application and ecosystem with minimal costs incurred. What we have now, after three years, is a budding SAAS platform that I enjoy hacking away on when I get the chance to. I also mentor junior developers on this organization's open-source projects and have helped those who have shown an interest to become the open-source collaborators they wish to be.

I also run monthly meetings for checking in with BikeTag Ambassadors from all over the world, coordinating with BikeTag Team members, and generally supporting the game of BikeTag in our pursuit to make the games easy for anyone and everyone to play!

As Co-Founder with my longtime friend Evan, we have started a project to compile and track all information about the game of BikeTag both in the past, how it moved from a photo tag game to a motorcycle-based photo tag game all over the world to now a regional/city-based photo tag game played by local communities. BikeTag.Org provides a way for anyone to play the game of BikeTag in a given region and recently launched in more than 20 new cities including; Vienna, Austria Vancouver, BC, Toulouse, France, Islamabad, Pakistan, and more! The BikeTag Project is more than a team of volunteers providing software and tools to enable the game of BikeTag, it is also a community of players of the game of BikeTag connected from all over the world.

I also upped my open-source game. github.com/biketagorg



Senior Software Engineer Contract

Ken Eucker LLC

Jan 2019 - Jan 2022 (3 years 1 month)

"All dogs are therapy dogs, some are just freelancing."

Principal engineer seeking remote-only contracts for computer software services ranging from web development to app development and more. I work with local small businesses in various markets. I also participate in the gig economy on UpWork by taking on remote, short-term, contracts while traveling the Pacific Northwest.



Senior Software Engineer

Ernst & Young Global Consulting Services

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021 (4 months)

Remote Contract Software Engineer attending daily check-ins with teammates and working on several projects throughout the weekday. Projects I have worked on during my time at EY include: A NodeJs web application complete with hanaDB backend and React frontend. The development for this project is using Typescript + Sass + HTML(tsx), and operates on SAP server infrastructure.



Senior Node Developer

Clevertech

Oct 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 3 months)

I worked on the Sam Harris website running on WordPress VIP and was brought onto the team to transition them away from WooCommerce to using Piano.IO and other platforms to manage subscriptions and analytics. During my time on the project, I developed tools in Node.JS to coordinate and compile the data for this migration and provide in-depth reports on the results.

100% Remote Engineer on a 100% Remote Team. I attend daily stand-ups with clients in New York, USA. I am available to clients for a six-hour work stretch each day of the workweek and outside of that, I choose what hours I work. I participate in sprint planning and estimating each week and do client demos each Friday of the week. I maintain a healthy work-life balance that would not be as successful if it wasn't for the dedication of Clevertech to the well-being of the team and team members.

Full-Stack Developer

Apr 2019 - Jun 2019 (3 months)

Full-stack development on a WordPress 5.0 website to be deployed on the WordPress VIP platform and follows the coding standards outlined for WordPress VIP. Custom theme and plugin development with the new, React-based, Gutenberg editor and integrated NodeJS build tools for compiling scripts for both the admin backend and the client frontend. The website featured stories and statistics about a company's diversity programs and included components built in React and d3.



Web Developer

Digital Trends Media Group

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 (1 year 11 months)

Full Stack Web Developer working in PHP, Node, HTML, and Javascript on a WordPress platform that serves content to over 5,000 concurrent users a day. In my primary role as a shared resource for another department in the organization, I develop solutions and maintain integrations for all of the needs of that department including automating processes. Daily participant in standup meetings, software project planning meetings, and system architecture meetings. As a self-starting leader on a team of leaders, I interface with stakeholders and other team members to continuously iterate on solutions that have a direct impact on our digital publication businesses.

During my time at Digital Trends, I developed a new ESP integration from the ground up using test driven development methodologies, refactored newsletter emails and the code that runs the signup modules on the site, implemented a couple of linking features on our articles, and implemented a new article type with a slideshow; all for the WordPress platform of digitaltrends.com.

My greatest work at Digital Trends is an end to end solution for encapsulating our ad code with site specific integration code and business logic which is deployed to AWS S3, Lambda, and API Gateway. A project that started as a skunkworks solution for my own process which I wholeheartedly developed into a fully-featured build automation tool.

I also upped my foosball game.

Freelance Software Engineer

Seven Twenty Studios LLC

Jun 2011 - Jan 2017 (5 years 8 months)

Custom software development and systems architecture engineer for web-connected technologies in both the business and personal sectors. I collaborate on small teams with diversely separate sets of skills to deliver websites. Project technologies include a focus on PHP, HTML, and MySql with equal

experience in C# and ASP.NET and MSSQL. I enjoy projects that enable efficient client-facing changes as well as automating underlying architecture decisions.

In 2014 I began contracting full-time as a remote employee. I continue to work on small teams as a collaborative developer as well as consulting with interactive producers to provide long-term architectural designs that benefit the business needs that clients are looking for. I enjoy developing code using github as an all-encompassing development solution and delivering solutions from design to version 2 iterations and anywhere in between.

Web Developer

Solid Digital | Web Design Agency

Mar 2016 - Dec 2016 (10 months)

Participated in client meetings, standups, development planning sessions, and company-wide strategy meetings as a web developer.

I was an active polyglot at Solid and I included myself on projects for the web using the Microsoft stack, PHP and Mysql stack, as well as pure HTML and Javascript website projects. I interfaced with project managers and clients to provide new features and implementations to existing sites as well as maintenance and issues that arise. In collaboration with other developers in the company, I participated in sprint planning, story and defect weighting, and tech roundtables about new and exciting technologies.



Contract Web Developer

R\West

Mar 2014 - Apr 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Backend web services developer and software architecture designer focusing on projects in php, mysql, javascript, and html. Developed concurrently on version one and version two implementations that saw growth and reached scalability. Agile methodologies and version control using github while working directly with server environments for deployment.



Software Development Engineer

Viewpoint

Dec 2011 - Jan 2014 (2 years 2 months)

Developer role in scrum process on systems team: attended daily scrums, participated in weighting sprints, defect ticket management.

Coordinated development efforts with Project Manager, Support, and Quality Assurance teams. Core development in ASP.NET C#, Multi-Tier SQL, VB.NET Winforms on flagship Viewpoint Construction Software.

I also upped my pool game.



Software Developer I

Overland Agency

May 2010 - Jul 2011 (1 year 3 months)

Team developer and scrum participant. Worked mostly in bug fixing, qa testing, and technical design contributor of a proprietary CMS offering customizations for various clients. Worked within ASP.NET and MSSQL for both client and server-side enhancements to existing projects.

Lead Silverlight development for all projects: "Fresh Local Music" Delivered a Silverlight out of browser music app that runs on laptops in the store locations and updates external database.

Education



Margon Institute of Technology

Bachelors of Science, Software Engineering Technology 2006-2010 2006 - 2010

Skills

Web Development • JavaScript • Node.js • Agile Methodologies • Scrum • Software Design • Object Oriented Design • Software Engineering • User Interface Design • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)